### Paula Rodríguez Cloud engineer

- ★ linkedin.com/pauloba
- ★ github.com/pauloba
- ★ stackoverflow.com/pauloba

I have a degree in Computer science from Vigo University. In 2017 I got into Cloud Computing and I've been working with: Docker, K8s, Istio, Terraform, Helm, Jenkins. I have hands-on experience in technical support and system administration, especially with GCP.

#### **Experience**

#### FonYou [ Jul 2021 - now ] Cloud Sysadmin

Deployment, operation and support for cloud-based production systems, ensuring the availability, performance, scalability and security of the systems.

Automation of processes and operations + support and maintenance of company-developed applications.

#### **Tech stack**

Languages

Galician - native

Spanish - native

Catalan - proficient

English - proficient

Polish - entry level

Kubernetes
Terraform
gitFlow
Jenkins
Docker
Helm
SOL

#### Methodologies

IaC + CI/CD
Kaizen
Agile (Scrum)
Git flow
Peer review
Merge Requests
DevSecOps
security checks
vulnerability monitoring
clean/maintainable code

#### Google through Webhelp [Jan 2019 - June 2021]

#### **Subject Matter Expert**

Help customers troubleshoot and fix GCP integrations.

Bug reporting (internal tools), and bug quality review.

Mentor and guide colleagues to improve the support service quality, within SLAs and SLOs.

Create, improve and maintain internal documentation.

Internal training for the infrastructure team.

#### Google through Sellbytel [ Aug 2017 - Jan 2019 ]

#### **Technical Solutions Representative**

Triage, diagnosis and solution of issues related to services of customers hosted in GCP, through email, phone and Hangouts.

Experience with a Salesforce-based ticketing system.

Technologies: GCE, GKE, VPC networks, Container Registry, Deployment manager, Pub/Sub, GCP APIs, IAM & Security.

#### **Experience**

#### Soft skills

# Empathy Teamwork Work ethic Critical thinking Active listening Documentation Resourcefulness

#### Enxendra Technologies [Nov 2016 - Apr 2017]

#### Level 2 support and QA unit testing

Patch deployment, UNIX sysadmin (syslog, tomcat, crontab, ssh).

Java unit testing with Groovy and Spock.

Experience with the Atlassian stack: Jira, confluence, bitbucket.

Technologies: docker, IntelliJ, eclipse, SoapUI, postman, MySQL, Java, Ant, Maven, SpringBoot, Groovy and Spock.

#### **Education**

## Computer science degree at <u>UVigo</u> [ 2012 - 2016 ] Final project pauloba/latch-plugin-mediawiki

High level trade school, Computer Programming at CPR Daniel Castelao [ 2003 - 2005 ]

Professional training course: Java Programmer and analyst 11 months [2011]

#### Telefónica Security Op. Center

#### [ Nov 2015 - Oct 2016 ] Level 2 security technician

Coordination with CSIRT / CERT, ISPs, web hostings, registrars and registrants to stop and prevent global fraud attempts.

Incident reporting: analysis and reports for final customers.

Real time network monitoring and security incident analysis with Cisco FirePOWER/SourceFire/FireSight sources for QRadar.

QRadar (IBM SIEM) rule adjustment to fine-tune detections.

Online fraud prevention: referer analysis, bank transfer analysis, monitoring of suspicious phishing connections.

Real time analysis and mitigation for Bank Trojans, halcash.

Experience with the SIRIOS ticketing system and ITSM Remedy.

#### National Association for Information Security

[Jan - Sept 2015] General Secretary

The **project** was motivated by approval of BOE-A-2015-344

Website sysadmin via Wordpress panel and ssh.

Merchandising design w/Gimp+Inkscape: t-shirts, banners, logo.

#### **Experience**

#### Conferences

#### Organizing committee

r2con [ 2017 - 2020 ]

Merchandising Schedule planning

#### r2con2020 website

Community manager
Organizing speakers/trainers
Audio testing w/music artists

#### Attendee

CCC [ 2017 - 2020 ]

GSIC Sec. Conference [ 2012 ] RootedCON [ 2012 - 2017 ]

#### Vigo University [ 2010 – 2013 ] Sysadmin

Installation, config. and maintenance of the Campus softw/hard.

Management of LDAP systems, SquirrelMail, print servers, network monitoring software.

Restoration and recovery of hardware from old computers.

Network backup management with Clonezilla + Norton Ghost.

Tech support for students and teachers of the Campus labs.

#### Self-employment [ 2007 - 2015 ] Teacher

English and mathematics teacher for high school students.